CORY PIETTE

Phone: (717) 379-8517 | Email: coryjpiette@gmail.com | Mechanicsburg, PA 17050 LinkedIn/in/cory-piette-mba-30a6071b0/ | GitHub Profile: https://github.com/cory/piette Portfolio of Work: github.com/coryjpiette/Work-Portfolio

SUMMARY

Digital content and marketing specialist with experience in SEO optimization, content mapping, social media marketing, and "A/B" testing. Bachelor of Science in Biomedical Engineering from Johns Hopkins University and MBA from Penn State University. Certificate in Web Development, technologies - including HTML, CSS, JavaScript from Johns Hopkins University. Successfully published online articles, blogs and marketing materials for global corporations and leading world news sites. Works well independently and in teams, in large or small organizations. Former accomplished financial analyst and financial industry writer. Published author of "techno-thriller" novels.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Data Analytics • Database Management • Programming • SEO • Social Media Marketing • Financial Analysis and Advising • Biotechnology • Risk Management

SKILLS/TECHNOLOGIES

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Bulma, GitHub, MySQL, R Programming, MS Office (Advanced Knowledge of Excel), Microsoft D365, Visual Basic

RELEVANT PROJECTS

FlixFinder! | github.com/TroyBohrer8/Project-1 | Deployed: troybohrer8.github.io/Project-1

- Summary: Searchable database that provides movie and TV show information
- Role: Front-end designer
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Bulma, Google Fonts, Photoshop

Weather Forecast | github.com/coryjpiette/Weather | Deployed: coryjpiette.github.io/Weather

- Summary: Weather app that provides current and 5-day weather forecasts.
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, API, AJAX, Bootstrap, Font Awesome

Coding Quiz | github.com/coryjpiette/Code-Quiz | Deployed: coryjpiette.github.io/Code-Quiz

- Summary: Tests the user's knowledge of basic coding concepts via a timed, multiple-choice quiz.
- Role: Sole Author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, API, AJAX, Bootstrap, Font Awesome

EXPERIENCE

Author May 2021 - Present

Contracted to Austin Macauley Publishers, LLC.

Republishing of Techno-thriller novel, The Demeter Initiative, originally published in July 2017

Freelance Technical/Content Writer

Jan 2016 - Present

Mechanicsburg, PA

- Contracted by over 30 companies that provide content creation, marketing materials, and technical reports
- Create content used for websites, online articles/blogs, social media posts, and marketing emails.
- Range of topics includes finance, tax strategies, real estate, biotechnology, information technology, data analytics, and supply chain operations.

Regional Finance and Supply Chain Management Walmart Corporate

Mar 2020 - Apr 2021

Mechanicsburg, PA

- Prepared over 50 regional supply chain and inventory accuracy reports and internal instructional materials.
- Monitored and prevented inventory "shrinkage" due to inventory miscalculations, theft, and shipping errors.
- Analyzed regional product placement accuracy, inventory efficiency, and resulting accounting ramifications.

Managing Partner/Co-owner

May 2017 - Feb 2020

Imperial Media Solutions (social media marketing consulting)

Enola/Mechanicsburg, PA

- Prepared written content for over 500 advertisements.
- Analyzed demographic information to determine best target audiences for online marketing advertisements.
- Advised on software programming required to collect applicable data.
- Calculated online marketing "click-through" rate efficiency for budgeting/financing purposes.

Financial Professional

Jan 2015- Dec 2015

Prudential Insurance Company of America

Camp Hill, PA

- Advised on a full spectrum of investment and insurance products including equities, bonds, exchanged-traded funds, mutual funds, 401(k) plans, 403(b) plans, 529 plans, as well as alternative investments such as options.
- Performed portfolio management and asset allocation to achieve clients' short and long-term goals.
- Structured life insurance policies; including whole and term life, variable, and annuity plans.

Senior Consultant

Nov 2013 - Dec 2014

Public Resources Advisory Group

Mechanicsburg, PA (Contracted Satellite Office of Firm headquartered in NY, NY)

- Created and presented financial marketing materials to over 15 state agencies.
- Designed and implemented strategic, long-term fiscal recovery plans for financially burdened entities.
- Priced and executed a series of complex call options using propriety option valuation models.
- Prepared weekly department reports on investment performance.

Financial Advisor

Mar 2012 - Oct 2013

Waddell & Reed, Inc.

Harrisburg, PA

- Developed and managed client relationships and conducted financial planning keyed to individual requirements.
- Advised on a full spectrum of investment and insurance products including equities, bonds, exchanged-traded Funds, mutual funds, 401(k) plans, 403(b) plans, 529 plans, as well as alternative investments such as options.
- Performed portfolio management and asset allocation to achieve clients' short- and long-term goals.

EDUCATION

Johns Hopkins University (Baltimore, MD)

Sep 1996 – May 2000

Bachelor of Science, Biomedical Engineering, with concentration in Materials Science and Engineering

Penn State University (Middletown, PA)

Jan 2016 – Dec 2017

Master's in Business Administration, Finance concentration; degree awarded December 2017.

Johns Hopkins University, Whiting School of Engineering

May 2021 - Nov 2021

Intensive 6-month certificate program in web development using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, and Amazon Web Services.

01

equitie